Joseph Burgess, Software Engineer

+44 77693 25254 josephburgess@gmail.com Github London

After spending 8+ years in corporate and financial PR, what was previously an obsessive hobby has become my full-time focus, and I've finally taken the plunge to pursue a new challenge in the tech industry. From building PCs for friends and family to experimenting with home servers and automating tasks with scripting, I've always looked for ways to make life easier and more efficient with technology. I just graduated from Makers Academy having built some pretty cool stuff along the way, and am now eager to apply my skills and experience to new, interesting projects. Some of the tech I enjoy using is shown below, but check out my <u>Github</u> for a more comprehensive picture.































Software Engineering Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAKERS; LONDON – NOV 2022 – MAR 2023

- Learned the fundamental principles of software engineering, such as OOP, TDD and SOLID, as well as Agile and XP methodologies.
- Spent time building several projects using a broad range of languages and frameworks.
- Successfully collaborated with other learners to identify realistic MVPs and deliver them to deadlines.

Projects

Name	Description	Technologies Used	Purpose/Goal
Step Free Gigs	Mobile app that finds wheelchair accessible gigs in London with step-free navigation	React Native, Expo, Node.js, Express.js, Jest	Final project at Makers Academy, build a mobile app from the ground up, utilising several API calls while learning a new tech-stack.
Acebook Air	A social media app built with the MERN stack	MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Mongoose, Render(deployment), Multer, Jest, Cypress	Build a full-stack web application using the MERN stack and improve experience working in an agile, collaborative environment.
Bank Tech Test	A command-line banking application, part of the Tech Test solo week, week 10 of Makers	TypeScript, Jest, ts-node	Focus on a project with less time constraints in order to focus on rigorous TDD and clean readable code. I also took this week as an opportunity to learn TypeScript.
<u>Database Server</u>	Simple key-value store app providing two endpoints to set and get key-value pairs.	Python, Flask, MongoDB, Pytest	Improving understanding of Python syntax and building simple back-ends using Python/Flask

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Python, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React, React Native, Flask, Jest, Cypress, Pytest, Sinatra, Rails

Database: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Devops: Docker, TravisCI, AWS, Render, Heroku

Previous Professional Experience

In my former roles I have advised a huge number of companies, ranging from small tech startups, to FTSE 250 listed businesses on their strategy around fundraising. I helped clients to communicate their investment case in a clear and compelling way. This 8+ year career has given me a huge amount of transferrable experience. I learned to adapt well to rapidly changing work requirements and am a great project/time manager. I have also honed my EQ down to a fine art. PR is a relationships business, and I thrive working in diverse teams and love collaborating to solve tough problems.

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR, HOUSTON PUBLIC RELATIONS; LONDON - NOV 2021 - NOV 2022

- Corporate and financial communications specialist, advising a huge range of companies on their comms strategy
- Capital Markets PR team, reporting directly into Board Director, direct report for several members of team
- Helping clients to raise money both through private and public markets
- Clients across multiple sectors including Gaming, Resources, Healthcare, Financial Services, Tech

ASSOCIATE PARTNER, YELLOW JERSEY PR; LONDON - SEP 2016 - NOV 2021

- Communications, media relations and investor relations specialist
- Working with Companies in a number of countries including dual listings on TSX and ASX
- Worked on +10 IPOs, listing on LSE (Premium Main Market and Standard List) AIM and NEX

SENIOR ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE, HUDSON SANDLER; LONDON — SEP 2015 – SEP 2016

- Clients across multiple sectors and regions, including large Russian institutions
- Organisation and management of client events, capital markets days and campaigns
- Content editor for company website and social media. Part of web design team building new website

EQUITIES OPERATIONS ANALYST, MORGAN STANLEY; NEW YORK — AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- Trading desk assistant for ETF and Financial Arbitrage teams within the Institutional Equity Division
- Responsible for the life cycle of each trade from placement to settlement, reconciling front-to back issues

UNDERWRITING ASSISTANT, LIBERTY MUTUAL; SINGAPORE AND SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA — AUGUST 2012-13

• Rotation between Marine Cargo, Energy Fire & Construction, and Casualty, and Professional Indemnity departments working alongside the active underwriter

QUALITY ASSURANCE ASSOCIATE, SEGA OF EUROPE; LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM — SEP 2009 - JUL 2012

• QA tester on AAA titles across multiple platforms, a high-pressure, highly technical role working in a large team

Education

MBA INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS (DISTINCTION) - THE MOUNTBATTEN INSTITUTE (2014-15) NEW YORK, USA 12 MONTHS / BANGKOK, THAILAND - 4 MONTHS SEP-DEC

Dissertation Title: "The Role of Innovation Diffusion Factors on the rise of Bitcoin. Should we be paying attention to cryptocurrencies?"

Awards: 'The Lady Edwina Mountbatten Award for the Best Dissertation in the Graduating Class of December 2015'

BA ECONOMICS (2:1) - UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX -- BRIGHTON, UK (2010-14)

Dissertation Title: "Quantitative analysis of football attendance figures in the English Premier League - should teams sell more tickets?"